Jacky Tsai (Chi-Ying Tsai)

Taichung City, Taiwan +886-965-520510

Jacky.cy.tsai@gmail.com

https://jackycytsai.github.io/Portfolio.github.io/

Summary

A data analyst with 3+ years of experience in financial analysis and data analysis. Passionate about data analysis and business intelligence. Versed in Python, SQL, Tableau, and Data Studio. Able to manage, process, analyse and visualise data, and also experienced applying machine learning on business issues to provide insights.

Working Experience

foodpanda Taipei, Taiwan 2021/07 – 2022/02 **Data Analyst**

- Support Customer Experience and Operation Team to build and maintain dashboards for tracking customer satisfaction and product performance.
- Designed web crawlers with Python to collect customer voices on social media and app stores to analyse the issue from customer view.
- Cooperated with fraud and legal teams to detect unusual activities. Analysed fraud behaviour, seted threshold and built monitors to prevent wastage, which detected NT\$ 700,000+ fraud in a month.
- Conducted text mining on user feedback, built ML models to classify text content and analyse content sentiment. Provided the manager with an efficient way to capture 200k+ user feedback to improve product defects and increased 3~5% satisfaction score.

Credit Analyst

Bank SinoPac

Taipei, Taiwan

2018/10 - 2019/03

Analysed corporation financial statement and collected relevant market information to evaluate client business operation status.

Auditor, Associate II

PricewaterhouseCooper Taipei, Taiwan

2017/09 – 2018/09

Acted as a team leader to support the client in adjusting their accounting system. Corrected the cost allocation problems and revised clients' financial statements from loss to profit.

Auditor, Associate I

Ernst & Young

2016/09 - 2017/09

Introduced data analytic tools in annual audit projects and provided insight on financial performance.

Education

University of Southampton

UK

2019/09 - 2020/09

MSc Business Analytics and Management Sciences

Professional Skills

Data Analytics

- Data Pre-process, Statistic Analysis, Data Visualisation, Data Modelling
- Python, SQL, BigQuery, Data Studio, Tableau

Machine Learning

- Conduct exploratory data analysis, feature engineering, and trained data to build forecast models.
- Perform text mining, design models to quantify content in Chinese, and analyse content sentiment.

Web scraping

Program with Python to build web scraping tools for collecting public information such as social media and app comments.